[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to
trient tasa Advanced
Training as you all know I've started
publishing series of YouTube videos
covering some of the realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of
obstacles and how can we solve those
obstacles by using trient tasa while
automating your test cases this is our
obstacle 10 in terms of real time
scenarios and this is
our lesson 52 in terms of overall trient
tosa automation training so in this
lesson I'm going to talk about how can
we solve an obstacle where you need need
to extract the text while extracting the
text you need to exclude the dynamic
portion of the text and you need to
buffer the dynamic portion of the text
and enter the buffered Dynamic portion
of the text into an edict box so this is
our real time scenario please do
subscribe to the channel click on Bell
icon you'll receive notifications
whenever I publish more videos
thank
you this is our 10th
obstacle which is named as extracting
text and categorized as easy so now let
us go for it so let us first understand
what is the challenge that we need to
solve for please automate a test step
taking the total amount shown in the
success message and enter it into the
text box so so this is your success
message that displays whenever you land
land on this
page and we need to take the amount from
this success message and you need to
enter the same
amount in this edit box right as soon as
you enter you solve this automation
problem so here the challenge is
whenever I say let me retry then your
amount keeps on changing so here partial
text from here to here and then from
here to here is static and the amount is
dynamic so we need to capture this
Dynamic amount and enter in the text box
if you enter the correct amount then
your automation problem solves
successfully okay so now let us go back
to our trient
tasa and as you all know we are
capturing all the objects under
obstacles folder so for that let's now
let us right click on this obstacles
folder select scan and application so
that we can capture the objects that are
required to automate our test
case so this is our application select
the application click on
scan and Here If You observe closely I
can see enter total amount edit box here
right but I'm not finding this object
purchase completed so I'm not finding
this object to find that object let us
expand the filters how by clicking
towards right this one right and some
more okay now if you scroll
down here you can see enter total amount
this is our edit box see I highlight see
it's highlighting here this is our edit
box and
then sorry when I'm highlighting this
see the edit box is getting highlighted
now what is our static text our static
text is this one which is div container
okay so let's select this and let me
highlight this okay let's highlight this
one see this is the static text okay
remove the
Highlight now if You observe closely
here when I select this one says the
selected item is unique and also the
edit box where we are entering the
amount that is
also identified uniquely but one change
we are going to do here what is that for
this this is dynamic message right where
the amount keeps on changing that's why
what I'm going to do I'm going to rename
this
as purchase
completed message that is one thing and
if you see the identify by the
properties right I can see ID is
selected and inner text also selected
but this inner text keep on changing
right let's say if I take this
property then whenever there is a change
in the message then tasar cannot
identify the object so for that what I'm
going to do I'm going to remove this in
text I'm going to remove this inner text
I don't want to consider this inner text
property because because this inner text
property keeps on changing I'm
considering ID and tag let us make sure
still this object is uniquely identified
see even though I remove this inner text
still my object is uniquely
identified done now let's go back to the
top and let's rename this module the
best practice is to rename the module
every time let's copy this obstacle name
and paste here name the module with the
obstacle name okay so
now save this particular
module we saved it close the module
let's go back to Tri and tasa so this is
the new module that we captured okay so
I can see here I have purchase completed
message enter total amount both now let
us come back to our blue section test
case section right click on this
obstacles
folder let's create a new test case and
name this as obstacle name that we
copied
earlier double click on this test case
now to create test steps what we need to
follow you need to Simply drag this
module and drop onto your test case to
form the test steps now let's expand
this so now what is is our
first action we need to do we need to
capture this message first right and
once you capture this message you need
to extract the only amount from the
captured message for that what I'm going
to do I'm going to start
using inner text property how come here
this is my
object open the drop- down
select inner
text equal to what is the inner text let
me copy this entire inner text copy this
and then paste here now as I told you
earlier here the inner text whatever the
inner text we have here right here this
entire this entire portion is static
until
dollar and this is dynamic and this
entire portion is again static so that's
why what I'm going to do here here I
would like to
replace let me do one thing here okay
let me expand this so here this static
part I don't want to touch I'm doing now
this is your Dynamic part right so I
would like to verify this entire text
here okay I'm going to select the action
mode as verified but because this is a
dynamic portion I would like to exclude
this Dynamic portion while verifying it
but while excluding this Dynamic portion
I would like to store this Dynamic
portion to a buffer so how can we do
that by using X buffer concept how let's
go here this Dynamic portion I would
like to replace with open curly braces
XB is X buffer see this is XB that means
exclude this portion and
buffer this Dynamic portion into a
buffer name called amount so that's why
open Square braces amount close Square
braces and close your curly braces
verify this entire
text while verifying this text I would
like to exclude this Dynamic
portion but I would like to store this
Dynamic portion into a buffer that's why
I'm using a method called XB if you want
to just buffer then you are going to use
just B capital B but I would like to
exclude
this portion and buffer this portion
into a buffer name called
amount that's why I'm using the method
XB so
now here I'm storing the dynamic portion
into a buffer right now our next action
is I need to enter the stored buffer
value in edit box so for that simply
call the buffer name called amount here
open curly braces capital B open Square
Braes this is my buffer name amount
close Square Braes close curly bra done
and your action mode is
input so let's save this let me do one
thing let me run this and see what
happens okay right click and run in
scratchbook
see now can see
here we have
entered the same number here
10657 now let me run one more time just
keep this in mind 15 3199 okay so let's
close this one run this again right
click and
run 15 3199
okay so I mean it's it's very fast you
are not even able to see what it entered
but it entered correctly see 1531 99
okay so hope you all understand the
concept right so here you can see here
now let me see the test result here if
you expand the test
result what is the we are storing XB
amount where see here we are excluding
this 15 3199 here and the same amount we
are entering here okay so if you have
any queries leave your queries in the
comment box I'll try to respond your
queries
[Music]